Guide to the Humanities and Fine Arts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- ALBERT S. COOK
  - Book: The Old English Elene, Phoenix, and Physiologus (edited by Cook) - review of, [1919?] (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Correspondence
    - Adams, Anthony, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - (To) Angell, James R., 1921 (Box 5)
    - (To) Baldwin (Dr.), 1906 (Box 5)
    - Bouquillon, Thomas, 1898 (Box 5)
    - Bright, James W. (Modern Language Association), 1894-1907 (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Brooke, Tucker, 1915, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Broughton, Leslee Nathan, 1925-1926 (Box 5)
    - Brown, Edward Miles, 1902, 1905 (Box 5)
    - Bryce, James, 1904 (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Burgert, Edward, 1920, 1923 (Box 5)
    - Butter, Horace C., 1910 (Box 5)
    - Callaway, Morgan, Jr., 1919 (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - Campbell, Killis, 1912 (Box 5)
    - Carter, Henry Holland, 1923 (Box 5)
    - Collins, J.C., 1897 (Box 5)
    - Cooper, Lane, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Cram, Ralph Adams, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Crane, Thomas Frederick, 1890 (Box 5)
    - Crow, Charles L. and S.E. Burkhard, 1899 (Box 5)
    - [J.S.] Cushing and Company (bill), 1885 (Box 5)
    - Dawson, Samuel Edward, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - [J.J.M. deGroot?], 1911 (Box 5)
    - (To) Demarest (President), 1920 (Box 5)
    - Dwight, Timothy, 1893, 1897 (Box 5)
    - Eaton, George F., 1922 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Emerson, Oliver F., 1903, 1906 (Box 5)
    - Feuillerat, Albert Gabriel, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Freeman, Edward A., 1880 (Box 5)
    - Frowde, Henry (Oxford University Press), 1905 (Box 5)
    - Furness, Horace Howard, 1907, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Gibbons, James (Cardinal), 1898 (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Gibson, John, 1914 (Box 5)
    - Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1882 (Box 5)
    - Ginn, Heath, and Company (Ginn and Company), 1882-1927 (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Good, Caroline, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Goodell, Thomas Dwight, 1896, undated (Box 5)
    - Gosse, Edmund, 1909 (Box 5)
    - Grandgent, Charles Hall, [1914] (Box 5)
    - Hamilton, George L., 1920 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Hadley, Arthur T., 1895 (Box 5)
    - Harper, William Rainey, 1890 (Box 5)
    - Harris, Ellen J., undated (Box 5)
    - Hart, James Morgan (copy of letter to Ginn and Company), 1886 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Henry Holt and Company, 1912 (Box 5)
    - Henry, [V.], 1901 (Box 5)
    - Hewison, James King, 1911-1914 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Hickey, Emily H., 1905 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Hill, A.S., 1882 (Box 5)
    - (To) Hoag (Mr.), 1922 (Box 5)
    - Hoppin, J.M., 1898-1901 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Houghton Mifflin Company (enclosing letter from W.J. Rolfe), 1908 (Box 5)
    - Hulme, William Henry, 1900 (Box 5)
    - Jackson, Abraham Valentine Williams, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Jente, Richard, 1922 (Box 5)
    - Jones, H. Stuart Vedder, 1912 (Box 5)
    - Keogh, Andrew, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Kittredge, George Lyman, 1898-1899, 1919 (Box 5)
    - Klaeber, Frederick, 1901-1926 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Ladd, George Trumbull, 1897 (Box 6, Folder 107)
    - Lang, Henry Roseman, 1916 (Box 6)
    - Lanman, Charles R., 1881-1882, 1914, 1918, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 108)
    - Lawrence, William H., 1912 (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - Lewis, Charles M., 1899 (Box 6)
    - Lloyd, David, 1912 (Box 6)
    - London University, Vice-Chancellor, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Loomis, Roger Sherman, 1918 (Box 6)
    - Luce, Morton, 1907-1916, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Macbeth, Donald, 1915-1916 (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - McKenzie, Kenneth, 1907, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - Maclehose, James, 1914 (Box 6)
    - March, Francis Andrew, 1882 (Box 6)
    - Mayhew, Anthony L., 1891 (Box 6, Folder 114)
    - Mead, William Edward, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Menner, Robert J., 1922 (Box 6)
    - Milford, Humphrey Sumner (Clarendon Press), 1903 (Box 6)
    - Miller, Frank Justus, 1899 (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - Moffat, Douglas M., 1925, undated (Box 6)
    - Morelfatio, Alfred, 1902 (Box 6, Folder 116)
    - Morris, E.P., undated (Box 6)
    - Munger, Theodore Thornton, 1893 (Box 6)
    - Murray, James A.K., 1881-1882, 1888-1889, 1897-1898, 1906 (Box 6, Folder 117)
    - Napier, Arthur S., 1888, 1898-1899 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - The Nation (payment for article), undated (Box 6)
    - Neilson, William Allan, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Osborn, George A., 1912 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Oxon, W., 1889 (Box 6)
    - Osgood, Charles G., 1899, 1903-1904, 1907, 1916, 1921-1923 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - Oxford University Press (American Branch), 1905 (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Palmer, George Herbert, 1899, 1904, 1908 (Box 6)
    - Perrin, B., 1911 (Box 6)
    - Phelps, William Lyon, 1908, 1913, 1926 (Box 6)
    - Phillips, Andrew W., 1905 (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Phoutrides, Aristides E., 1923 (Box 6)
    - Plummer, Charles, 1906 (Box 6)
    - Powell, Frederick York, 1888, 1891, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Rea, John D., 1923 (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - Record, Samuel J., 1925 (Box 6)
    - Ridgway, Robert, 1915 (Box 6)
    - (To) Reid, W.T., 1882 (Box 6, Folder 125)
    - Root, Robert K., 1923 (Box 6)
    - Rivoizol, Giovanni Teresio, 1919 (Box 6)
    - Shachford, Martha Hale, 1910, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - Schleich, Gustav, 1911 (Box 6)
    - Seymour, Thomas Dudley, 1894 (Box 6)
    - Sievers, Edward, 1882-1891 (Box 6, Folder 127)
    - Silver, Burdett, and Company, 1897 (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - Spingarn, Joel Elias, 1923 (Box 6)
    - Stafford (Justice), 1923 (Box 6)
    - Starr, Ellen Gates (fragment), 1909 (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - Stevenson, William Henry, 1906 (Box 6)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1915 (Box 6)
    - Strunk, William, Jr., 1903 (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - Sweet, Henry, 1881, 1885-1886 (Box 6)
    - Sypherd, Wilbur Owen, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Thomas, Calvin, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - Toy, Crawford Howell, 1894 (Box 6)
    - Tupper, Frederick, 1920 (Box 6)
    - (To) Wager, Charles Henry Adams, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - Waller, Alfred Rayney (University Press, Cambridge), 1917-1918 (Box 6)
    - Warren, Minton, 1882, 1906 (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - Wells, John Edwin, 1916, 1918, 1927 (Box 6)
    - Wetmore, Monroe Nichols, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - White, Constance, 1916 (Box 6)
    - Whitman, Charles Huntington, 1905 (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Whitney, William Dwight, 1891 (Box 6)
    - Wilson, James, 1914-1915 (Box 6)
    - Woodbine, George Edward, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - Wright, Mary, 1909 (Box 6)
    - Wyatt, Alfred John, 1911 (Box 6)
    - Yale Co-operative Corporation, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - Yale University Library, 1921-1924 (Box 6)
    - Unidentified, 1881-1882, 1911, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - Acknowledgements of receipt of review by Cook of "The Runic Roods of Ruthwell and Bewcastle" by J.K. Hewison, from various libraries, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - Form letter from Cook and others, concerning a book club, 1886 (Box 6, Folder 140)
  - Correspondence of others
    - To Cook, Mildred E. (daughter) from Wedel, Theodore O., 1965 (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - To O'Hare, John J., from D.C. Heath and Company, 1925 (Box 6)
    - Reid, W.T. (President of the University of California), with: (Box 6, Folder 142)
      - Beers, Henry A., 1882 (Box 6)
      - Cooper, Jacob, 1882 (Box 6)
      - Gilman, Daniel, 1882, undated (Box 6)
      - Kellogg, M., 1882 (Box 6)
      - Lanman, Charles R., 1882 (Box 6)
      - March, F.A., 1882 (Box 6)
      - Warren, Minton, 1882 (Box 6)
    - Warren, Minton, with (Box 6, Folder 143)
      - Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1882, undated (Box 6)
      - Stebbins, Horatio, 1882 (Box 6)
  - Examinations (printed and draft), 1883-1885 (Box 6, Folder 144)
  - Notebook, Göttingen, Germany, 1877-1878 (Box 6, Folder 145)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, undated (Box 6, Folder 146)
  - Printed matter relating to Cook, 1889, 1899 (Box 6, Folder 147)
  - Printed matter, miscellaneous, 1877, 1884, 1888-1889, 1901, 1907, 1919, 1922, undated (Box 6, Folder 148)
  - Program for "The Knight of the Burning Pestle" by Beaumont and Fletcher, 1898 (Box 6, Folder 149)
  - Recommendations for Yale University Library, 1922, undated (Box 6, Folder 150)
  - Student paper on Cynewulf by James M. Lindeman, undated (Box 6, Folder 151)
- TRACY PECK
  - Correspondence
    - B., C., 1901, 1894, 1898, undated (Box 7, Folder 152)
    - Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 153)
    - Conway, Moncure D., 1906 (Box 7)
    - Dexter, T.B., 1880 (Box 7, Folder 154)
    - Dwight, Timothy, 1892, 1896 (Box 7)
    - Evans, Jennie A., 1890 (Box 7, Folder 155)
    - Falconio, D., Cardinal, 1912 (Box 7)
    - Farnam, William W. [Treasurer, Yale], 1894 (Box 7)
    - Flagg, Isaac, 1889-1891 (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - Frieze, Henry S., 1887, 1889 (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - Gaet, Caroline M. (and others), 1911 (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - Gori, Cornelius, 1908 (Box 7)
    - Hadley, Arthur, 1906, 1908 (Box 7, Folder 159)
    - Hawes, Edward S., 1897 (Box 7)
    - Heritage, Ruth (Lucius), 1891 (Box 7)
    - H., 1885 (Box 7, Folder 160)
    - Houghton, Mifflin, and Company, 1881 (Box 7)
    - Ireland, Archbishop John, 1901, 1906, undated (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - L., undated (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - [McLane?], J.W., 1890 (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - [Olin?], Charles P., 1885 (Box 7)
    - Preston, Harriet W., 1880, [1889] (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Packard, Lewis R., 1883, 1884 (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - Peck, E. (brother), 1849 (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - Peck, Epaphroditus (nephew), 1921 (Box 7)
    - Peck, Kezia A., 1893, 1861-1864, 1867-1869 (Box 7, Folder 167-167b)
    - Peck, Lillie H. (née Hall - Peck's wife), 1870, 1879, 1883, 1886, 1892-1893 (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - Peck, Sally (mother), 1874 (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Peck, Teresina (daughter), 1890-1894 (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - Peck, Tracy (father), 1861 (Box 7, Folder 170A)
    - Perrin, B., 1880, 1885 (Box 7, Folder 171)
    - Perry, Bliss ( Atlantic Monthly ), 1905 (Box 7)
    - Rathbone, Elizabeth A. (cousin), 1891 (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - [Rigero, Ella?], 1891 (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - S., 1891 (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - Sachs, Julius, 1880 (Box 7)
    - Sage, H. [M?], 1892 (Box 7)
    - Sheldon, Winthrop D., 1905 (Box 7)
    - Stebbins, Elisa C., 1889 (Box 7)
    - Slattery, J.R., 1901 (Box 7, Folder 175)
    - Smith, Clement L., 1890, 1893, 1901-1907 (Box 7)
    - Sympathy letters on the death of Peck's son, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 176)
    - T, 1874, 1877, 1897, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 177)
    - Taft, William H., 1907 (Box 7, Folder 178)
    - Thacher, Thomas A., 1880, 1883, undated (Box 7)
    - [Venable, W.H.?], 1874 (Box 7, Folder 179)
    - Wheeler, Benjamin I., 1892 (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - White, Horace [copies], 1899 (Box 7)
    - Yale Alumni Weekly, 1906 (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - Unidentified, [1921?] (Box 7, Folder 182)
    - Unidentified [family members?], 1886, undated (Box 7, Folder 183)
  - Correspondence of others
    - Adams, Joseph (Peck's maternal grandfather) with: Peck, Tracy (Peck's father), including letters concerning Peck's birth, 1813, 1815, 1838 (Box 7, Folder 184)
    - To Peck, Miles L., from Keene, Francis B. (American Consul-General, Rome, Italy), 1921 (Box 7, Folder 185)
    - Rowell, Teresina (Peck's daughter)
      - From A. - C., 1921-1923, undated (Box 7, Folder 186)
      - From D. - H., 1921-1922 (Box 7, Folder 187)
      - From I. - M., 1921-1922 (Box 7, Folder 188)
      - From N. - R., 1921-1922 (Box 7, Folder 189)
      - From S. - W., 1921-1922 (Box 7, Folder 190)
      - From unidentified and first names only, 1921-1923, undated (Box 7, Folder 191)
  - Notes
    - "Pliny, Jr.,", 1896 (Box 7, Folder 192)
    - "Cornelia Africani of [Gracchorin?],", undated (Box 7)
    - Tivoli and Horace, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 193)
    - Roman Archaeology, 1899-1905 (Box 7)
    - Monte [Cavo], 1915 (Box 7, Folder 194)
    - Abbey at the Grotta Ferrata and the Caput (Box 7)
    - Ferentinae near Marino, 1916 (Box 7)
    - Epitaphs of the Scipios, 1917 (Box 7)
    - Eivia's Villa and Castel Giubileo, 1918 (Box 7)
    - re: Roman history and Latin language, undated (Box 7, Folder 195)
    - re: Unique position of Ennius in Roman literature, language, and history, undated (Box 7)
    - Forum, undated (Box 7, Folder 196)
    - Roman coins, undated (Box 7)
    - Latin Philology, early Latin, undated (Box 7, Folder 197)
    - Lucretius, undated (Box 8, Folder 198)
    - Miscellaneous re: Roman history and Latin language, undated (Box 8, Folder 199)
  - Notebook re: stocks and bonds, 1881-1921 (Box 8, Folder 200)
  - Writings
    - "Communicatia" (poem), 1856 (Box 8, Folder 201)
    - Poem delivered at the festival of the Society of the B.B.'s, 1858 (Box 8)
    - "The Man of Sorrows" (poem), 1859 (Box 8)
    - "The Claims of the English Language,", 1861 (Box 8, Folder 202)
    - Valedictory address, 1861 (Box 8)
    - "Frederick Ritschl,", 1862 (Box 8, Folder 203)
    - "On the Authorship of the Dialogus De Oratoribus,", 1879 (Box 8, Folder 204)
    - "Notes on Latin Quantity,", 1882 (Box 8)
    - "Alliteration in Latin,", 1884 (Box 8)
    - "The Classics and the Yale Curriculum,", 1885 (Box 8)
    - "Notes on Graduate Instruction,", 1892 (Box 8, Folder 205)
    - "C. Plinius Marcellino Suo S.,", 1892 (Box 8)
    - "Cicero's Hexameters,", 1897 (Box 8)
    - "Gleanings from Roman Epitaphs," Journal of the British and American Archaeological Society of Rome, 1899 (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - "The Personal Address in Roman Epitaphs," Journal of the British and American Archaeological Society of Rome, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 207)
    - "Professions and Trades in Roman Epitaphs," Journal of the British and American Archaeological Society of Rome, 1913 (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - "Archaeological Gleanings from the Diary of Pius II,", 1914 (Box 8, Folder 209)
    - "Pius II and his Commentarii" (presented to the British and American Archaeological Society of Rome), 1914 (Box 8)
    - "The Argiletum and the Roman Book-Trade" (presented to the British and American Archaeological Society of Rome), 1914 (Box 8, Folder 210)
    - "Ennius,", undated (Box 8, Folder 211)
    - "The Annals of Ennius,", undated (Box 8)
    - Translation of part of Tennyson's "Ulysses" into Latin verse, undated (Box 8, Folder 212)
  - Memorabilia, 1901, 1917, undated (Box 8, Folder 213)
  - Printed matter re: Peck's death, 1921, undated (Box 8, Folder 214)
  - Printed matter re: Pope Pius II, 1905 (Box 8, Folder 215)
  - Photographs, 1886, 1888 (Box 8, Folder 216)
  - Contracts, advertisements, and receipts for articles and books by Peck, 1874-1904 (Box 8, Folder 217)
  - Journal of the British and American Archaeological Society of Rome, 1908-1911 (Box 8, Folder 218)
    General
    See also: Writings for additional issues of this journal
- FREDERICK B. KAYE
  - Biographical material - newspaper clippings, 1925, 1930, undated (Box 9, Folder 219)
  - Correspondence
    - Babbitt, Irving, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 220)
    - Baldensperger, F., 1925 (Box 9)
    - Cross, Wilbur L. (Yale Graduate School), 1925 (Box 9)
    - [Esdail?], Arundell, 1925 (Box 9)
    - [Golistein?], J., 1925 (Box 9)
    - Havens, Raymond D., 1925 (Box 9)
    - "C.B.J.,", 1925 (Box 9)
    - Lovejoy, Arthur O., 1922, 1924 (Box 9)
    - Lowes, John L., 1926 (Box 9, Folder 221)
    - Manly, John M., 1925 (Box 9)
    - Moore, C.A., 1926 (Box 9)
    - Northwestern University, 1925 (Box 9)
    - [Orage?], S.R., 1925 (Box 9)
    - Phelps, [N.L.?], 1925 (Box 9)
    - Redman, Ben Ray, 1925 (Box 9)
    - Sarett, [Lew?], 1925 (Box 9, Folder 222)
    - Saurat, D., 1925 (Box 9)
    - Smith, D. Nichol, 1925 (Box 9)
    - Tinker, Chauncey B., 1925 (Box 9)
    - Young, Karl, 1925 (Box 9)
    - (To)_____, Henry, 1914 (Box 9)
    - (To)_____, Margaret, 1912 (Box 9)
    - (From) Unidentified, 1925, undated (Box 9)
  - Photographs, printed matter, miscellaneous, 1925
    See: box 9A (Oversize)
  - Writings
    - Article (reprint): "The Influence of Bernard Mandeville,", 1922 January (Box 9, Folder 224)
    - Book: A Census of British Newspapers and Periodicals, 1620-1800, written with R.S. Crane with the assistance of M.E. Prior, reviews, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 225)
    - Book edited by Kaye: The Fable of the Bees by Bernard Mandeville, reviews, 1925-1926 (Box 9, Folder 226)
    - Debate speeches, dramatic sketches, and other miscellaneous writings, 1913, undated (Box 9, Folder 227)
      - "First Performance of the Craig-Puppet Show. Thursday, March 22, 1913, at 8 P.M. MACBETH. Grand Opera in 5 Acts and 11 Scenes, in Esperanto, by Federigo De Kugelmannis, founded on a play by William Shakspere [sic]," 10 pp. (Box 9)
      - "A Respectable Wake," 14pp., undated. Author's name written as "Frederick Stern, 688 Yale Station, New Haven, Conn." (Box 9)
      - "The Hermit and His Messiah" By F.B. Kugelman, undated, 6pp. & title p. (Box 9)
      - Debate speech: "I desire to prove that next year Freshmen should be compelled to room on the Campus," 4pp., undated. (Box 9)
      - "Second Speech for the Affirmative," undated, 7pp. re workmen's compensation laws. (Box 9)
      - Literary notes and lists of books by Arnold Bennett, Hugh Walpole, Frank Swinnerton, and Somerset Maugham, undated, 4pp. (Box 9)
      - Musical performance notes, undated, 4pp. (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous notes and fragments, 10pp. (Box 9)
    - Essays and short stories (including some fragments), 1913, undated (Box 9, Folder 228)
    - Notes: list of Italian drawings, undated (Box 9, Folder 229)
    - Notes: copies of various manuscripts by Mandeville (made by Kaye), undated (Box 9, Folder 230)
    - Thesis (M.A.) (bound) "Introduction to the interpretation of William Blake,", 1916 (Box 9, Folder 231)
  - Additional biographical material (Box 9, Folder 219)
    - 3 letters (electrostatic copies) to the editor of the Northwestern Alumni News with recollections of Kaye by former students, 1975 (Box 9)
    - Northwestern Alumni News. Spring and Fall 1975. With articles on Kaye (Box 9)
  - Oversize material: photographs, printed matter, miscellaneous (Box 9A, Folder 223)
- RICHARD THAYER HOLBROOK
  - Scrapbook: Published reviews of and correspondence about: Boys and Men at Yale, (1900), Dante and the Animal Kingdom, (1902), The Farce of Master Pierre Patelin, trans., (1905), 1900-1912 (Box 10, Folder 232)
  - Scrapbook: Published reviews of and correspondence about: Portraits of Dante (1911), 1911-1928 (Box 10, Folder 233)
  - Correspondence of Rudolph Altrocchi re: Dante and R.T. Holbrook, 1936, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 234)
  - Letters of Holbrook to Rudolph Altrocchi, 1921-1933 (Box 11, Folder 235)
  - Review of The Portraits of Dante by Frank Jewett Mather (tipped in to front of volume), 1922 (Box 11, Folder 236)
  - Photographs (Box 11, Folder 237)
  - Dante Portrait: drawings, photo, and newsclipping about (Box 11, Folder 238)
  - Newsclippings on the death of Holbrook, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 239)
- EUGENE O'NEILL, JR.
  - Lecture notebooks: (Box 12, Folder 240)
    - Greek Tragedy (Box 12)
    - Plato and Aristotle (Box 12)
    - Classical Civilization (Box 12)
    - Homer and Greek History (Box 12)
    - Age of Reason and Age of Romance (Box 12)
- IRENE WEIR
  Scope and Contents
  The number of items are contained in parentheses before the unitdate.
  - Correspondence
    - General (9 items), 1912, 1922, 1925-1926, 1931, 1934, undated (Box 13, Folder 241)
    - Unidentified (1 item), 1937 (Box 13)
    - Arms, John T. (1 item), 1930 (Box 13, Folder 242)
    - Hendricks, Helen (1 item), 1936 (Box 13)
    - Lewis, May (1 item), 1932 (Box 13)
    - Niemeyer, J.H. (1 item), 1906 (Box 13)
    - Perry, Edith W. (1 item), 1939 (Box 13)
    - Announcements, catalogues, and programs (Box 13, Folder 243)
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings re: Irene Weir (Box 13, Folder 244)
    - Photographs of paintings by Irene Weir (Box 13, Folder 245)
    - Miscellaneous photos and printed Matter (Box 13, Folder 246)